<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brain-body | Biolelectronics at MIT</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/tag/brain-body/</link><atom:link href="https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/tag/brain-body/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Brain-body</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/images/logo_hu824973b0e9eedfd7e339f3ab3f0c6ec4_36236_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Brain-body</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/tag/brain-body/</link></image><item><title>New research center focused on brain-body relationship established at MIT</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2022-brain-body-center/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2022-brain-body-center/</guid><description>&lt;p>The inextricable link between our brains and our bodies has been gaining increasing recognition among researchers and clinicians over recent years. Studies have shown that the brain-body pathway is bidirectional — meaning that our mental state can influence our physical health and vice versa. But exactly how the two interact is less clear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A new research center at MIT, funded by a $38 million gift to the McGovern Institute for Brain Research from philanthropist K. Lisa Yang, aims to unlock this mystery by creating and applying novel tools to explore the multidirectional, multilevel interplay between the brain and other body organ systems. This gift expands Yang’s exceptional philanthropic support of human health and basic science research at MIT over the past five years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Lisa Yang’s visionary gift enables MIT scientists and engineers to pioneer revolutionary technologies and undertake rigorous investigations into the brain&amp;rsquo;s complex relationship with other organ systems,” says MIT President L. Rafael Reif. “Lisa’s tremendous generosity empowers MIT scientists to make pivotal breakthroughs in brain and biomedical research and, collectively, improve human health on a grand scale.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://yangtan.mit.edu/k-lisa-yang-brain-body-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">K. Lisa Yang Brain-Body Center&lt;/a> will be directed by Polina Anikeeva, professor of materials science and engineering and brain and cognitive sciences at MIT and an associate investigator at the McGovern Institute. The center will harness the power of MIT’s collaborative, interdisciplinary life sciences research and engineering community to focus on complex conditions and diseases affecting both the body and brain, with a goal of unearthing knowledge of biological mechanisms that will lead to promising therapeutic options.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/k-lisa-yang-brain-body-center-established-mit-0525" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full story&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>