<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Atharva Sahasrabudhe | Biolelectronics at MIT</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/author/atharva-sahasrabudhe/</link><atom:link href="https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/author/atharva-sahasrabudhe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Atharva Sahasrabudhe</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/images/logo_hu824973b0e9eedfd7e339f3ab3f0c6ec4_36236_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Atharva Sahasrabudhe</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/author/atharva-sahasrabudhe/</link></image><item><title>A multifunctional tool for cognitive neuroscience</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-10-19_indie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-10-19_indie/</guid><description>&lt;p>A team of researchers at MIT’s McGovern and Picower Institutes has advanced the clinical potential of a thin, flexible fiber designed to simultaneously monitor and manipulate neural activity at targeted sites in the brain. The collaborative team improved upon an earlier model of the multifunctional fiber, developed in the lab of McGovern Institute Associate Investigator Polina Anikeeva, to explore dynamic changes to neural signaling as large animals engage in a working memory task. The results appear Oct. 6 in &lt;a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adh0974" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Science Advances&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new device, developed by Indie Garwood, who recently received her PhD in the Harvard-MIT Program in Health Sciences and Technology, includes four microelectrodes for detecting neural activity and two microfluidic channels through which drugs can be delivered. This means scientists can deliver a drug that alters neural signaling within a particular part of the brain, then monitor the consequences for local brain activity. This technology was a collaborative effort between Anikeeva, who is also the Matoula S. Salapatas Professor in Materials Science and Engineering and a professor of brain and cognitive sciences, and Picower Institute Investigators Emery Brown and Earl Miller, who jointly supervised Garwood to develop a multifunctional neurotechnology for larger and translational animal models, which are necessary to investigate the neural circuits that underlie high-level cognitive functions. With further development and testing, similar devices might one day be deployed to diagnose or treat brain disorders in human patients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://mcgovern.mit.edu/2023/10/19/a-multifunctional-tool-for-cognitive-neuroscience/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full story&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soft optical fibers block pain while moving and stretching with the body</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-10-19_soft-optical-fiber/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-10-19_soft-optical-fiber/</guid><description>&lt;p>Scientists have a new tool to precisely illuminate the roots of nerve pain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Engineers at MIT have developed soft and implantable fibers that can deliver light to major nerves through the body. When these nerves are genetically manipulated to respond to light, the fibers can send pulses of light to the nerves to inhibit pain. The optical fibers are flexible and stretch with the body.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new fibers are meant as an experimental tool that can be used by scientists to explore the causes and potential treatments for peripheral nerve disorders in animal models. Peripheral nerve pain can occur when nerves outside the brain and spinal cord are damaged, resulting in tingling, numbness, and pain in affected limbs. Peripheral neuropathy is estimated to affect more than 20 million people in the United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Current devices used to study nerve disorders are made of stiff materials that constrain movement, so that we can’t really study spinal cord injury and recovery if pain is involved,” says Siyuan Rao, assistant professor of biomedical engineering at the University of Massachusetts at Amherst, who carried out part of the work as a postdoc at MIT. “Our fibers can adapt to natural motion and do their work while not limiting the motion of the subject. That can give us more precise information.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Now, people have a tool to study the diseases related to the peripheral nervous system, in very dynamic, natural, and unconstrained conditions,” adds Xinyue Liu PhD ’22, who is now an assistant professor at Michigan State University (MSU).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Details of their team’s new fibers are reported today (&lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-023-02020-9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nat. Methods&lt;/a>) in a study appearing in Nature Methods. Rao’s and Liu’s MIT co-authors include Atharva Sahasrabudhe, a graduate student in chemistry; Xuanhe Zhao, professor of mechanical engineering and civil and environmental engineering; and Polina Anikeeva, professor of materials science and engineering, along with others at MSU, UMass-Amherst, Harvard Medical School, and the National Institutes of Health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/soft-optical-fibers-nerve-related-pain-1019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full story&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multifunctional fibers enable modulation of cortical and deep brain activity during cognitive behavior in macaques</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/garwood-2022-multifunctional/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/garwood-2022-multifunctional/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Magnetic robots walk, crawl, and swim</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-magnetic-robot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-magnetic-robot/</guid><description>&lt;p>MIT scientists have developed tiny, soft-bodied robots that can be controlled with a weak magnet. The robots, formed from rubbery magnetic spirals, can be programmed to walk, crawl, swim — all in response to a simple, easy-to-apply magnetic field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“This is the first time this has been done, to be able to control three-dimensional locomotion of robots with a one-dimensional magnetic field,” says Professor Polina Anikeeva, whose team published an open-access paper on the magnetic robots June 3 in the journal Advanced Materials. “And because they are predominantly composed of polymer and polymers are soft, you don’t need a very large magnetic field to activate them. It’s actually a really tiny magnetic field that drives these robots,” adds Anikeeva, who is a professor of materials science and engineering and brain and cognitive sciences at MIT, a McGovern Institute for Brain Research associate investigator, as well as the associate director of MIT’s Research Laboratory of Electronics and director of MIT’s &lt;a href="https://yangtan.mit.edu/k-lisa-yang-brain-body-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">K. Lisa Yang Brain-Body Center&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new robots are well suited to transport cargo through confined spaces and their rubber bodies are gentle on fragile environments, opening the possibility that the technology could be developed for biomedical applications. Anikeeva and her team have made their robots millimeters long, but she says the same approach could be used to produce much smaller robots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/magnetic-robots-walk-crawl-swim-0707" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full story&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multifunctional microelectronic fibers enable wireless modulation of gut and brain neural circuits</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/shahriari-2023-multifunctional/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/shahriari-2023-multifunctional/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Unraveling connections between the brain and gut</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-gut-fiber/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-gut-fiber/</guid><description>&lt;p>The brain and the digestive tract are in constant communication, relaying signals that help to control feeding and other behaviors. This extensive communication network also influences our mental state and has been implicated in many neurological disorders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIT engineers have designed a new technology for probing those connections. Using fibers embedded with a variety of sensors, as well as light sources for optogenetic stimulation, the researchers have shown that they can control neural circuits connecting the gut and the brain, in mice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a new study, the researchers demonstrated that they could induce feelings of fullness or reward-seeking behavior in mice by manipulating cells of the intestine. In future work, they hope to explore some of the correlations that have been observed between digestive health and neurological conditions such as autism and Parkinson’s disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“The exciting thing here is that we now have technology that can drive gut function and behaviors such as feeding. More importantly, we have the ability to start accessing the crosstalk between the gut and the brain with the millisecond precision of optogenetics, and we can do it in behaving animals,” says Polina Anikeeva, the Matoula S. Salapatas Professor in Materials Science and Engineering, a professor of brain and cognitive sciences, director of the K. Lisa Yang Brain-Body Center, associate director of MIT’s Research Laboratory of Electronics, and a member of MIT’s McGovern Institute for Brain Research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anikeeva is the senior author of the new study, which appears today in Nature Biotechnology. The paper’s lead authors are MIT graduate student Atharva Sahasrabudhe, Duke University postdoc Laura Rupprecht, MIT postdoc Sirma Orguc, and former MIT postdoc Tural Khudiyev.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/unraveling-connections-between-brain-gut-0622" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full story&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnetically Actuated Fiber‐Based Soft Robots</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/lee-2023-softrobots/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/lee-2023-softrobots/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The preference for sugar over sweetener depends on a gut sensor cell</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/buchanan-2022-preference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 17:03:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/buchanan-2022-preference/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Modular Integration of Hydrogel Neural Interfaces</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/tabet-2021-integration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/tabet-2021-integration/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Electrochemical Modulation of Carbon Monoxide-Mediated Cell Signaling</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/park-2021-modulation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/park-2021-modulation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Customizing Multifunctional Neural Interfaces through Thermal Drawing Process</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/antonini-2021-customizing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/antonini-2021-customizing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Modular Integration of Hydrogel Neural Interfaces</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/tabet-2021-modular/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/tabet-2021-modular/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Remotely controlled proton generation for neuromodulation</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/park-2020-remotely/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/park-2020-remotely/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gaseous Messenger Molecule</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2020-gaseous-messenger-molecule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2020-gaseous-messenger-molecule/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nitric oxide is an important signaling molecule in the body, with a role in building nervous system connections that contribute to learning and memory. It also functions as a messenger in the cardiovascular and immune systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it has been difficult for researchers to study exactly what its role is in these systems and how it functions. Because it is a gas, there has been no practical way to direct it to specific individual cells in order to observe its effects. Now, a team of scientists and engineers at MIT and elsewhere has found a way of generating the gas at precisely targeted locations inside the body, potentially opening new lines of research on this essential molecule’s effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The findings are reported today in the journal Nature Nanotechnology, in a paper by MIT professors Polina Anikeeva, Karthish Manthiram, and Yoel Fink; graduate student Jimin Park; postdoc Kyoungsuk Jin; and 10 others at MIT and in Taiwan, Japan, and Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://news.mit.edu/2020/nitric-oxide-messenger-molecule-inside-body-demand-0629" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full story&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In situ electrochemical generation of nitric oxide for neuronal modulation</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/park-2020-in-situ/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/park-2020-in-situ/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A gut sensor for sugar preference</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/buchanan-2020-gut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/buchanan-2020-gut/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>