<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Magnetic Nanoparticles | Biolelectronics at MIT</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/tag/magnetic-nanoparticles/</link><atom:link href="https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/tag/magnetic-nanoparticles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Magnetic Nanoparticles</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/images/logo_hu824973b0e9eedfd7e339f3ab3f0c6ec4_36236_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Magnetic Nanoparticles</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/tag/magnetic-nanoparticles/</link></image><item><title>Tiny magnetic discs offer remote brain stimulation without transgenes</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2024-10-11_magnetoelectric/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2024-10-11_magnetoelectric/</guid><description>&lt;p>Novel magnetic nanodiscs could provide a much less invasive way of stimulating parts of the brain, paving the way for stimulation therapies without implants or genetic modification, MIT researchers report.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The scientists envision that the tiny discs, which are about 250 nanometers across (about 1/500 the width of a human hair), would be injected directly into the desired location in the brain. From there, they could be activated at any time simply by applying a magnetic field outside the body. The new particles could quickly find applications in biomedical research, and eventually, after sufficient testing, might be applied to clinical uses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The development of these nanoparticles is described in the journal Nature Nanotechnology, in a paper by Polina Anikeeva, a professor in MIT’s departments of Materials Science and Engineering and Brain and Cognitive Sciences, graduate student Ye Ji Kim, and 17 others at MIT and in Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://dmse.mit.edu/news/tiny-magnetic-discs-offer-remote-brain-stimulation-without-transgenes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full story&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41565-024-01798-9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Link to the paper&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://mcgovern.mit.edu/2024/10/11/tiny-magnetic-discs-offer-remote-brain-stimulation-without-transgenes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">McGovern Institute News&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/tiny-magnetic-discs-offer-remote-brain-stimulation-without-transgenes-1011" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MIT News&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnetic robots walk, crawl, and swim</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-magnetic-robot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-magnetic-robot/</guid><description>&lt;p>MIT scientists have developed tiny, soft-bodied robots that can be controlled with a weak magnet. The robots, formed from rubbery magnetic spirals, can be programmed to walk, crawl, swim — all in response to a simple, easy-to-apply magnetic field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“This is the first time this has been done, to be able to control three-dimensional locomotion of robots with a one-dimensional magnetic field,” says Professor Polina Anikeeva, whose team published an open-access paper on the magnetic robots June 3 in the journal Advanced Materials. “And because they are predominantly composed of polymer and polymers are soft, you don’t need a very large magnetic field to activate them. It’s actually a really tiny magnetic field that drives these robots,” adds Anikeeva, who is a professor of materials science and engineering and brain and cognitive sciences at MIT, a McGovern Institute for Brain Research associate investigator, as well as the associate director of MIT’s Research Laboratory of Electronics and director of MIT’s &lt;a href="https://yangtan.mit.edu/k-lisa-yang-brain-body-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">K. Lisa Yang Brain-Body Center&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new robots are well suited to transport cargo through confined spaces and their rubber bodies are gentle on fragile environments, opening the possibility that the technology could be developed for biomedical applications. Anikeeva and her team have made their robots millimeters long, but she says the same approach could be used to produce much smaller robots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/magnetic-robots-walk-crawl-swim-0707" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full story&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>