<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Indie Garwood | Biolelectronics at MIT</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/author/indie-garwood/</link><atom:link href="https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/author/indie-garwood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Indie Garwood</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/images/logo_hu824973b0e9eedfd7e339f3ab3f0c6ec4_36236_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Indie Garwood</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/author/indie-garwood/</link></image><item><title>Magnetic robots walk, crawl, and swim</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-magnetic-robot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-magnetic-robot/</guid><description>&lt;p>MIT scientists have developed tiny, soft-bodied robots that can be controlled with a weak magnet. The robots, formed from rubbery magnetic spirals, can be programmed to walk, crawl, swim — all in response to a simple, easy-to-apply magnetic field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“This is the first time this has been done, to be able to control three-dimensional locomotion of robots with a one-dimensional magnetic field,” says Professor Polina Anikeeva, whose team published an open-access paper on the magnetic robots June 3 in the journal Advanced Materials. “And because they are predominantly composed of polymer and polymers are soft, you don’t need a very large magnetic field to activate them. It’s actually a really tiny magnetic field that drives these robots,” adds Anikeeva, who is a professor of materials science and engineering and brain and cognitive sciences at MIT, a McGovern Institute for Brain Research associate investigator, as well as the associate director of MIT’s Research Laboratory of Electronics and director of MIT’s &lt;a href="https://yangtan.mit.edu/k-lisa-yang-brain-body-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">K. Lisa Yang Brain-Body Center&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new robots are well suited to transport cargo through confined spaces and their rubber bodies are gentle on fragile environments, opening the possibility that the technology could be developed for biomedical applications. Anikeeva and her team have made their robots millimeters long, but she says the same approach could be used to produce much smaller robots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/magnetic-robots-walk-crawl-swim-0707" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full story&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnetically Actuated Fiber‐Based Soft Robots</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/lee-2023-softrobots/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/lee-2023-softrobots/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Indie's defense</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-05-08-indie-defense/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-05-08-indie-defense/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congratulations to Indie on a successful thesis defense on &amp;ldquo;Probing the depths of unconsciousness with multifunctional neurotechnology&amp;rdquo; at the MGH Ether Dome!!!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multifunctional fibers enable modulation of cortical and deep brain activity during cognitive behavior in macaques</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/garwood-2022-multifunctional/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/garwood-2022-multifunctional/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Customizing Multifunctional Neural Interfaces through Thermal Drawing Process</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/antonini-2021-customizing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/antonini-2021-customizing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Controlling drug activity with light</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2020-drug-activity-control/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2020-drug-activity-control/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hormones and nutrients bind to receptors on cell surfaces by a lock-and-key mechanism that triggers intracellular events linked to that specific receptor. Drugs that mimic natural molecules are widely used to control these intracellular signaling mechanisms for therapy and in research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a recent publication, a team led by MIT Associate Professor Polina Anikeeva, a McGovern Institute for Brain Research Associate Investigator, and Oregon Health and Science University (OHSU) Research Assistant Professor James Frank introduce a microfiber technology to deliver and activate a drug that can be induced to bind its receptor by exposure to light.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://news.mit.edu/2020/controlling-drug-activity-light-1217" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full story&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In vivo photopharmacology enabled by multifunctional fibers</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/frank-2020-vivo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/publication/frank-2020-vivo/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>