<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Commitment to Diversity | Biolelectronics at MIT</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/diversity/</link><atom:link href="https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/diversity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Commitment to Diversity</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><image><url>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/images/logo_hu824973b0e9eedfd7e339f3ab3f0c6ec4_36236_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Commitment to Diversity</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/diversity/</link></image><item><title>Commitment to Diversity</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/diversity/diversity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/diversity/diversity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our group’s philosophy is that a team diverse in racial, socioeconomic, cultural, and gender identity can achieve far more than one that lacks diversity.
Each member of our group has a responsibility in upholding diversity:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Professor Anikeeva is committed to reducing bias in hiring practices and protecting the voices of each member of our group.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Graduate students and postdoctoral scholars are expected to build diverse collaborations both within and beyond our group. They are also expected to develop opportunities for the mentorship of diverse undergraduate scholars.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Undergraduates are encouraged to actively contribute to the scientific and cultural diversity of our group.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Every member of our group is required to respect each other’s perspectives with patience and understanding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Group members are prohibited from discriminating against any other member on the basis of sex, color, religion, race, sexual orientation, gender identity, disability, or age.
Group members are required to follow the nondiscrimination policy outlined in the &lt;a href="https://handbook.mit.edu/nondiscrimination" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MIT Handbook&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>