<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>McGovern News | Biolelectronics at MIT</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/tag/mcgovern-news/</link><atom:link href="https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/tag/mcgovern-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>McGovern News</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/images/logo_hu824973b0e9eedfd7e339f3ab3f0c6ec4_36236_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>McGovern News</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/tag/mcgovern-news/</link></image><item><title>A multifunctional tool for cognitive neuroscience</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-10-19_indie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/post/2023-10-19_indie/</guid><description>&lt;p>A team of researchers at MIT’s McGovern and Picower Institutes has advanced the clinical potential of a thin, flexible fiber designed to simultaneously monitor and manipulate neural activity at targeted sites in the brain. The collaborative team improved upon an earlier model of the multifunctional fiber, developed in the lab of McGovern Institute Associate Investigator Polina Anikeeva, to explore dynamic changes to neural signaling as large animals engage in a working memory task. The results appear Oct. 6 in &lt;a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adh0974" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Science Advances&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new device, developed by Indie Garwood, who recently received her PhD in the Harvard-MIT Program in Health Sciences and Technology, includes four microelectrodes for detecting neural activity and two microfluidic channels through which drugs can be delivered. This means scientists can deliver a drug that alters neural signaling within a particular part of the brain, then monitor the consequences for local brain activity. This technology was a collaborative effort between Anikeeva, who is also the Matoula S. Salapatas Professor in Materials Science and Engineering and a professor of brain and cognitive sciences, and Picower Institute Investigators Emery Brown and Earl Miller, who jointly supervised Garwood to develop a multifunctional neurotechnology for larger and translational animal models, which are necessary to investigate the neural circuits that underlie high-level cognitive functions. With further development and testing, similar devices might one day be deployed to diagnose or treat brain disorders in human patients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://mcgovern.mit.edu/2023/10/19/a-multifunctional-tool-for-cognitive-neuroscience/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full story&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>