<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research-topics | Biolelectronics at MIT</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/research-topic/</link><atom:link href="https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/research-topic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Research-topics</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/images/logo_hu824973b0e9eedfd7e339f3ab3f0c6ec4_36236_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Research-topics</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/research-topic/</link></image><item><title>Magnetic Nanotransducers</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/research-topic/1.magnetic-transducers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/research-topic/1.magnetic-transducers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Neuromodulation approaches available to the neuroscience community are either mechanically invasive (electrical stimulation), require transgenes (e.g. optogenetics, DREADDs), or lacking the resolution and cell-type specificity (ultrasound, transcranial magnetic stimulation). In our group we explore magnetic nanomaterials as transducers of wireless magnetic neuromodulation (&lt;a href="../../publication/chen-2015-wireless/">Science, 2015&lt;/a>). Due to its negligible magnetic susceptibility and low conductivity, biological matter is nearly transparent to weak magnetic fields (MFs) in alternating the low radiofrequency range (10s of kHz to 10s of MHz). Furthermore, it is well known in the field of cancer hyperthermia that magnetic nanoparticles (MNPs, 5-30 nm in diameter) can dissipate significant heat via hysteretic power loss in MFs. We leveraged this local heating to trigger heat-sensitive ion channels genetically introduced (&lt;a href="../../publication/chen-2015-wireless/">Science 2015&lt;/a>) or naturally present in electroactive cells (&lt;a href="../../publication/rosenfeld-2020-transgene/">Sci. Adv. 2020&lt;/a>). To achieve efficient heat dissipation and thus rapid neuronal activation, we have synthesized a broad palette of tertiary magnetic oxides with coercivities varying across three orders of magnitude (&lt;a href="../../publication/chen-2013-maximizing/">ACS Nano 2013&lt;/a>; &lt;a href="../../publication/chen-2016-high/">Nano Lett. 2016&lt;/a>) and developed a model for dynamic hysteresis in magnetic nanomaterials, which allowed us to tailor the conditions of alternating MF (&lt;a href="../../publication/christiansen-2017-practical/">Rev. Sci. Instr. 2017&lt;/a>) to the MNP properties. The latter lead to the idea of magnetothermal multiplexing (&lt;a href="publication/christiansen-2014-magnetically/">Appl. Phys. Lett. 2014&lt;/a>; &lt;a href="publication/moon-2020-magneothermal/">Adv. Funct. Mater. 2020&lt;/a>): the ability to independently heat (collocated) MNPs with different magnetic properties by using alternating MFs with distinct amplitudes and frequencies – a concept previously overlooked due to the use of linear models of hysteresis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to thermal stimulation of neural activity, we are leveraging hysteretic heat dissipation to enable local magnetically-driven delivery of pharmacological compounds to the membranes of neurons (&lt;a href="../../publication/romero-2016-localized/">Adv. Funct. Mater. 2016&lt;/a>). This concept was further generalized by encapsulating MNPs within thermo-sensitive liposomes that releases their pharmacological payloads in response to the remotely applied MFs. Loaded with ligands for the natural or engineered receptors, these magneto-liposomes could mediate local chemomagnetic modulation of neuronal activity, enabling wireless control of mouse behavior in assays of sociability and motivation (&lt;a href="../../publication/rao-2019-remotely/">Nat. Nanotechnol. 2019&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, we are exploring alternative means for using magnetic nanomaterials for neuromodulation, for example we are developing magnetic nanodiscs as transducers of mechanical stimuli under slow-varying MFs. Mechanical transduction mediated by magnetic nanomaterials demands either large MF gradients (~100 T/m) or particles with large magnetic moments. While the former is impractical in behaving subjects, the latter presents a challenge due to dipole-dipole interactions between single particle magnetic moments that render them colloidally unstable in solutions. We have addressed this challenge by developing anisotropic nanodiscs that in the absence of magnetic fields support a magnetic vortex state with zero net magnetization ensuring their colloidal stability. Upon application of weak, slow varying MFs, these particles assume in-plane magnetization and transduce torques to the cell membranes proportional to their magnetic volumes (&lt;a href="../../publication/gregurec-2019-tuning/">ACS Nano 2020&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multifunctional Fibers</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/research-topic/2.multifunctional-fibers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/research-topic/2.multifunctional-fibers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Currently available interface technologies for mapping of neural circuits suffer from fundamental limitations of low resolution, inability to perform multiple functions (recording, stimulation, drug delivery, chemical sensing etc.) simultaneously, and limited application space (i.e. cortex). Furthermore, the difference between the elastic and chemical properties of the neural tissues and the implanted probes results in a profound foreign body response and the formation of glial scars that isolate the devices from healthy tissue resulting in a loss of useful signal. By employing flexible and biocompatible neural probes we intend to address both the mechanical and chemical issues of neural recording devices. Furthermore, using simultaneous processing of multiple materials we can incorporate capabilities inaccessible to existing lithographically defined devices, such as simultaneous optical or pharmacological stimulation combine with high-resolution neural recording.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By leveraging recent advances in multi-material fiber-drawing processing traditionally used in telecommunications industry as well as photonics research, we combine polymers, metals and conductive composites to produce flexible probes incorporating conductive electrodes, optical waveguides and microfluidic channels (&lt;a href="../../publication/canales-2015-multifunctional/">Nat. Biotechnol. 2015&lt;/a>; &lt;a href="../../publication/park-2017-one/">Nat. Neurosci. 2017&lt;/a>). These multifunctional fiber-based probes with features as small as 5 µm allow, for the first time, for concomitant neural recording, optogenetic stimulation and drug delivery in the brain of freely moving mice, a set of capabilities indispensable in systems neuroscience, a field that aims to connect the dynamics of neural circuits to the observed behaviors. We are also working towards extending our fiber-probe technology to the applications in the peripheral nervous system and the spinal cord, which demand high flexibility and extremely low dimensions. Specifically, we were the first lab to demonstrate simultaneous neural recording and optogenetic stimulation in a mouse spinal cord that enabled direct optical control of lower limb muscles (&lt;a href="../../publication/lu-2014-polymer/">Adv. Funct. Mater. 2014&lt;/a>; &lt;a href="../../publication/lu-2017-flexible/">Sci. Adv. 2017&lt;/a>). Most recently, we have extended our flexible fiber-based tools to manipulation and monitoring of the circuits in the enteric (gut) nervous system (&lt;a href="../../publication/frank-2020-vivo/">bioRxiv 2020&lt;/a>), paving way to understanding the communication between the gut and the brain and to developing early diagnostics and treatments for conditions ranging from obesity to Parkinson’s disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To advance the studies of chemical neurotransmission, we are combining fiber-based tools with principles of photopharmacology and electrochemistry to achieve spatiotemporally precise generation of neuro-active compounds within specific regions of the nervous system. For instance, photoswitchable compounds have been instrumental in studies of receptors in neurons, but their potential in linking receptor function to behavior was not realized due to lack of tools for simultaneous light and drug delivery in moving subjects. To facilitate applications of photopharmacology in systems neuroscience, we have demonstrated control of reward behaviors in mice using miniature polymer fibers integrating waveguides and microfluidics (&lt;a href="../../publication/frank-2020-vivo/">bioRxiv 2020&lt;/a>). Gaseous neurochemicals such as a secondary messenger nitric oxide (NO) present a greater challenge to delivery into the brain. Inspired by catalysis of a metabolite nitrite into NO by enzymes containing iron-sulfur clusters in their cores, we have designed electrocatalytic fibers comprising cathodes decorated with platinum doped Fe3S4 nanoclusters and platinum anodes in addition to microfluidic channels. The Fe3S4-Pt nanoclusters within the electrocatalytic fibers were able to catalyze the generation of NO from the sodium nitrite solutions delivered via the same devices. We have applied these fibers to locally generate NO and control NO-mediated neural signaling in vitro and in vivo, paving way for studies of the role of this gaseous messenger in synaptic plasticity and metabolism (&lt;a href="../../publication/park-2020-in-situ/">Nat. Nanotechnol. 2020&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fiber-based Devices</title><link>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/research-topic/3.fiber-based-devices/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bioelectronics.mit.edu/research-topic/3.fiber-based-devices/</guid><description>&lt;p>In addition to neural interrogation, we are interested in using fiber-based all-polymer devices as scaffolds for neural tissue engineering and as potential replacements to the injured organs. The versatility of the fiber drawing process allows us to investigate the surface polarity and topographic structure of polymer-based nerve guidance channels on the axonal growth. Furthermore, we can design the fiber-based scaffolds to incorporate neural recording and optical neuromodulation capabilities. The latter may enable us to investigate the role of neural excitation on the axonal growth within the topographically controlled environment. We have recently found that optical neural excitation increases axonal growth by 3-4 fold, and furthermore exerts a directional bias on the growth of unstimulated tissues (&lt;a href="../../publication/park-2015-optogenetic/">Sci. Rep. 2015&lt;/a>). By combining this finding with the ability to optimize the scaffold geometry (&lt;a href="../../publication/koppes-2016-thermally/">Biomaterials 2016&lt;/a>) and nutrient transport (&lt;a href="../../publication/shahriari-2019-scalable/">Adv. Mater. 2019&lt;/a>) we intend to control the formation of synaptic connections between the neurons trapped within our scaffolds and the neurons within the brain, spinal cord or peripheral nerves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the goal of developing seamless interfaces between the prosthetic limbs and the injured nerves, we applied fiber fabrication to create light-weight fiber-based artificial muscles (&lt;a href="../../publication/kanik-2019-strain/">Science 2019&lt;/a>). These devices mimicking the structure of cucumber tendrils, are composed of bimorphs of an elastomer and a high-performance plastic with drastically different coefficients of thermal expansion that have been subjected to strains in excess of 700% to impart helical geometry. Upon an exposure to a moderate temperature increase (~10°C), these devices can respond with sub-second latencies lifting &amp;gt;600 times their weight.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>